Guide to the Lee Webb papers, 1969-1995.
Webb, Lee papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lee Webb papers, 1969-1995.
8465
Webb, Lee.
3.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, and institutional records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, and reports related to the New York State Urban Development Corporation. Also includes materials related to the New York State Job Development Authority.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lee Webb is a public policymaker. During the 1960s, Webb was active in the student, civil rights, and peace movements, serving as National Secretary of Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) beginning in 1963. After working as a journalist, he founded the Center for Public Policy Alternatives in Washington, D.C. in 1976. In 1984, Webb moved to New York to work for Governor Mario Cuomo, serving as Vice President and then Executive Vice President of the New York State Urban Development Corporation. He later served in health care management in Boston and as Vice President at the New School University in New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, and reports related to the New York State Urban Development Corporation. Also includes materials related to the New York State Job Development Authority.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Webb, Lee.; New York Job Development Authority.; New York State Urban Development Corporation.
Subjects:
Cities and towns -- Growth.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies Records, #6756.
CONTAINER LIST
- Speech material, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Speeches, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pre 1986 address book, 1986-10-01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- UDC 1 of 2, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- UDC 2 of 2, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- UDC reports, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- UDC rough notes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- UDC 1 of 2, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- UDC 2 of 2, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- UDC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- UDC, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- UDC, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- UDC annual reports, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- UDC annual reports, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- UDC annual reports, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- JDA annual reports, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Misc. publications, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- JDA meeting report and memoranda, 1994-11-22-1994-12-20 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- JDA meeting report and memoranda, 1994-10-18-1994-11-22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Optimizing the real estate function in a merged health care system, 1996-04-22 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Discussion to legislation, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Long Island public information briefing book, 1994-10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Audubon new community, UDC policy options, 1985-10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Temporary state commission on banking, insurance and financial services, 1984-02-15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- UDC meeting of the directors, 1994-12-15 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- NYS Banking, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- NYS Banking, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- NYS Banking, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Request for proposal, 1988-01-1988-02 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Media coverage, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Job development authority board, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- NYS economic development, 1984-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Message to the legislative, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Tele interview, 1985-04-08 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- New York State proposal for Toyota, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- UDC projects pictorial repertoire, Undated (Box 3)
- Speech Austin Texas, Energy conference, 1980-12 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  From county conferences and testimony to state legislatures
- Speech notes, National League of Cities, San Francisco, 1977-12-06 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Speech notes, CASLAAP, Oakland, CA, 1978-02-19 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Speech notes, Regional, Lincoln, NE, 1977-05-27-1977-05-29 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Speech notes, natural resources severance taxes, Billings, MT, 1980-02-10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Speech notes, National resources Coop Bank, National Center for Urban Ethics Affairs, 1979-12 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Revitalizing the American economy: Progressive supply-side program, 1981-11-14 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Energy conservation: the state and local agenda for the 1980's, 1981-05-13 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Talk, After the 1980 election what direction for the progressives, Minneapolis, MN, 1980-11-08 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Speech, Energy conservation and solar: A progressive agenda, Austin, TX, 1980-12-04 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Speech, Progressive electoral politics: Key issues and tasks, Cleveland, OH, 1980-11-22 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Speech notes, New strategy for Youngstown, OH, 1979-04-10 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Speech, Northeast conference of Black elected officials, Harrisburg, PA, 1982-06-03 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- A program of progressive federalism, New Orleans, LA, 1983-09-27 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- New ideas for MS-Tax and revenue strategies for the 1980's, Jackson, MS, 1985-01-31 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- New state economic development strategies, Madison, WI, 1985-02-04 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- New economic development ideas for Missouri, Jefferson City, MO, 1985-02-14 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- New ideas for Florida: Revenue strategies for the 1980's, Tallahassee, FL, 1985-05-03 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Banking deregulation: New ideas for Illinois, Springfield, IL, 1985-04-10 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Vermont politics, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Vermont correspondence
- Institute for policy studies, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Public power, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Vermont tax reforms, general, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Derek Shearer: The idea developer, 1974-04-22 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Hoff Energy Commission, 1973-11-1974-06 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Early national contacts, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Lifeline roles idea, 1974-01-1974-05 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Vermont capital gains tax on land speculation, 1974-01-30 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Vermont bank for cooperatives, 1975-06-08 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Health policy, insurance rates, 1974-01-1974-02 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- The tooth fairy bill, socialized dental care, 1973-10-10 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Beaudry/Steering Com., 6th annual national conference, 1980-03-24 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Conference planning and operations
- New techniques and technologies for political and community organizations, 1980-01-29 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Budgeted expenses October 1 1979 to September 20 1980, 1980-01-18 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- State legislative information service (SLIS), 1980-01-15 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Increasing the Stability and viability of small business, 1979-09-12 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Draft of progressive agenda for state and local governments on farm and land, 1979-09-04 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Evaluation of Philadelphia Conference and needed new decisions (Part I), 1979-08-20 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Energy and employment act of 1979, 1979-08-10 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Steering committee meeting, 1979-07-19 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Seizing the progressive opportunities, 1979-05-12 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- New Jersey Campaign '81 Draft, 1981-03-03 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Creating a 501 C4, 1981-01-12 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- State by state survey of results of 1980 state elections, 1980-11-28 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- New organizations and officials in Minnesota, 1980-11-25 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Suggested goals and programs for conference, 1980-07-07 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Possible subjects for bi-weekly conversations, 1980-06-27 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Creating database on S+L politics, 1980-01-20 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Suggested criteria for conference's choice of issues and project areas, 1980-06-25 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Western congressional targeting project, 1981-05-11 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Conference proposed programs, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- State politics memo, 1977-10-02 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Peter Hart proposed national survey on attitude to state and local government, 1976-09-16 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Early CASLAAP values notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
- New federalism and state and local government, Undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
- President Reagan's proposed block grant programs, 1981-05-19 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Self help development fund publications, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  Self help development fund
- Executive seminar on cooperatives and economic development, U.S. Congress, 1981-06-01 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Talk notes, monitoring the coop bank center for responsive governance, 1980-09 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Briefing for NY foundation a potential national consumer cooperative bank, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Speech notes, national consumer cooperative bank, Jackson, MS, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Speech notes, national consumer cooperative bank, Boston, MA, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Coop bank hearings, New York, 1982-10-22 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- The coop bank, 1978-07-31 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Changing farm, land, and food policies: a case for state and local action, Nashville TN, 1979-01-12 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  Political speeches
- Politics in the 1980's: the emerging political demography and its consequences, 1980-06 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Draft of political and electoral problems and opportunities for progressives, 1980-06-19 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Comments on California public employment retirement funds, 1979-08-20 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- The energy crisis and the 1980's, Oakland CA, 1981-04-02 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- State and local tax reform: the progressive agenda, 1978-10-07 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Homeownership protection act, model legislation, 1979-08 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- States, cities, and towns: the progressive's arena for the 1980's, 1982-01-09 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Suggested tasks for UAW-Liberal coalition, 1978-12-26 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Rebuilding the Roosevelt coalition: state and local governments' role, Washington D.C., 1982-03-07 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Issues beyond the 97th congress, 1981-07-24 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Federal initiatives for state and local tax reform, 1979-03-28 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Possible federal initiatives to assist development of urban housing, 1977-11-07 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Efforts to help Mondale campaign, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Inquiry magazine: democratic party politics, by David Osborne, 1981-07-06-1981-07-20 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- State energy act: a model bill for states, 1977-11 (Box 4, Folder 80)
- Publications catalog, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 81)
- Mother Jones magazines, 1976-02-1982-05 (Box 4, Folder 82)
- Memo: opportunities for progressives in the 1980's, 1980-06 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  Speeches drafts and notes
- Talk draft, new political constituencies, Midwest Academy, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 84)
- Employee ownership: an agenda for the states, 1980-12-09 (Box 4, Folder 85)
- State and local taxes: a progressive agenda, 1980-12-06 (Box 4, Folder 86)
- Talk notes, new political constituencies, UAW leaders, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Key issues at UAW legislative conference, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 88)
- Briefing the unions and progressives on new right state strategy, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 89)
- New farm and food policies, Nashville, TN, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 90)
- Keynote address: state and local tax reform: the progressive agenda, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 91)
- Rebuilding the Roosevelt coalition: state and local governments' role, 1982-07-03 (Box 4, Folder 92)
- Resources for democratic senate candidates in DC, DSCC issues conference, 1982-04-21 (Box 4, Folder 93)
- UAW_CAP meeting, Bloomington, IN, 1982-07-27 (Box 4, Folder 94)
- Mention of CASLP in fundraising letter, 1982-09-07 (Box 4, Folder 95)
- National association of home buildings, state and local model legislation, 1984-10-25 (Box 4, Folder 96)
- Trends in state and local government, 1985 and beyond, Washington DC, 1984-12-13 (Box 4, Folder 97)
- New national urban policy, 1977-10-27 (Box 4, Folder 98)
- Solar energy transfer amendment memo, 1977-10-05 (Box 4, Folder 99)
- Solar energy transfer amendment, 1977-08-17 (Box 4, Folder 100)
- Nuclear power plant conversion act, 1977-10-18 (Box 4, Folder 101)
- Cooperation on energy policy, 1977-10-28 (Box 4, Folder 102)
- Potential for using universal endowment funds, memo, 1977-11-07 (Box 4, Folder 103)
- Full employment through a national solar energy, energy conservation program, 1978-01-09 (Box 4, Folder 104)
- Community-owned mortgage banks, 1978-01 (Box 4, Folder 105)
- Using public employee pension funds for community and neighborhood development, 1978-03-16 (Box 4, Folder 106)
- Use of public employee pension funds, 1978-05 (Box 4, Folder 107)
- Energy conservation: new directions for cities, 1978-04-03 (Box 4, Folder 108)
- Proposed public employee pension funds investment strategy rural dev., 1978-08-16 (Box 4, Folder 109)
- Suggested tasks for UAW-Liberal coalition, 1978-12-26 (Box 4, Folder 110)
- Suggested IAM campaign on state and local tax reform, as a joint program, 1979-01-30 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Talk notes, American politics and parties, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Talk notes, American politics and parties, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Talk notes, CASLAAP Steerin Committee, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- State and local elections: new directions for citizen and labor organizations, 1980-11-23 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Citizen action conference proceedings, 1980-11-22-1980-11-23 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Speech draft, state and local elections: possible role for civic organization, 1980-11-23 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Remarks to Kennedy School fellows, 1979-03-07 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Talk notes, foundation for public affairs, 1979-04-17 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Reagan's new federalism: implications for progressives, 1982-02-25 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- States, cities, towns: progressive arena for the 1980's, 1982-01-09 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Speech at 5th national conference, Philadelphia, 1979-08-05 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Opening night speech, Denver national conference, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Notes, Episcopal bishops hearings, Washington DC, 1978-02-21 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Community mobilization and financing, 1981-06-23 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- CFA News, 1981-06-09 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Cleveland OH conference, 1977-06-03-1977-06-04 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- International association of machinist convention, 1979-01-22 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- MEA Legis. Conference, 1980-03-26 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- United Auto Workers Leg. Conference, Washington DC, 1979-01-16 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Food conference, New Haven, CT, 1978-06-10 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Denver national conference opening speech, 1977-07-07 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Rural life institute, Marshall, MN, 1978-06-20 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Introduction to public policy, Denver, CO, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Institute for policy studies retreat, 1978-03-10-1978-03-11 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Banking for non-bankers conference, Chicago, IL, 1977-06-10 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Norman foundation presentation, 1978-05-06 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Citizen participation: a historical perspective, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Tom Heyden's campaign for US senate in CA, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Saint Paul final speech, 1978-01-14 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Future of the progressive political movement, 1977-12-10 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Generic speech, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Issues beyond the 97th congress, CA democratic congressional delegation, national women's democratic club, 1981-07-24 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Remarks before SGAC on plant closings, 1981-11-22-1981-11-23 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Critical issues for 1982, spring conference for democratic candidates, 1981-12-12 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Energy crisis and the 80's: how state and local governments can take lead, 1981-04-02 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Speech at grant maker conference, David Hunter, New York, 1981-02 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- International association of machinist convention, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Homeownership protection act, 1979-08 (Box 5, Folder 39)